# Ricardo Jorge Fernandes da Silva Carlos (32)

Porto, Portugal (can relocate)
+351 913 387 296 • Skype: ricardo.j.carlos@gmail.com • email • LinkedIn

<u>GitHub - Portfolio</u>

#### **Personal statement**

I am transitioning from the Airline Industry, where I worked for the past 6 years, to Web & Mobile Developer and at present, I am looking to join a small team where I can learn, use my skills acquired and start as a junior developer. I'm challenging myself to always be up to date on the technological landscape with my self-learning ability.

In November 2016, I decided that I want to go for something more challenging than the work I was doing. I was always fascinated with programming and Mobile environments but never got around doing that. So, since then, I have been learning how to code and have gotten familiar with various parts of the Front end and Back end side of the development.

I recently finished a course of Web & Mobile developer, which includes HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and the Framework Bootstrap; Multi-Platform Mobile Application Development using Cordova, Ionic, Node.js, AngularJS; CMS of which Drupal and WordPress; Native Java Development for Android, SEO / SEM and more recently I'm finishing to learn AngularJS with the Ionic Framework for mobile development.

I'm a conscientious and professional person, with extremely high standards and eye for details, currently seeking a position that will make use of acquired skills with and opportunity for growth. A highly methodical and efficient individual, whose thorough and precise approach to work has yielded excellent results.

## **Key Skills**

- Proactive person who is able to work effectively under my own influence and stressful conditions
- Excellent communication skills, both written and verbal
- Self-motivated, efficient with high attention to details
- Problem-solving attitude
- Flexible in assignments
- Good eye for design
- Honest, dependable, reliable
- Fluent on Spanish and English, native Portuguese, learning Polish.

#### **Employment History**

## Web Developer - Orbitur/Laminar Madeiras, Porto - Portugal (Internship)

(*October 2017 – December 2017*)

#### Responsibilities:

- Redesign Laminarmad.com website using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, AngularJS and PHP;
- Good UX and modern design;
- Improving performance and accessibility;
- Lower the maintenance effort later on;

# Flight and Traffic Coordinator, Load Controller/Load Planner, Sky Handling Partner, London - UK (November 2014 – November 2016)

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Responsible for overseeing and co-ordinating the safe unloading/loading of the aircraft;
- Supervision, assistance with passenger services and passengers being directed to and from the aircraft in a safe manner:
- Weight and balance of aircraft, to include the loading instruction to ramp staff;

- Co-ordinating & recording the safe and timely delivery of all services to the aircraft including: Catering, Fuelling, Engineering, Cleaners, Toilet/Water servicing, Crew Transport and ground equipment;
- Responsible for the safe co-ordination of the pushback/start-up procedure on departure of the aircraft;
- Responsible for the timely sending of all movement messages following the aircrafts departure.
- LUFTHANSA OPS Basic Aircraft Handling Ramp Narrow Body and LH Regional Aircraft Certificate, issued by Lufthansa at Seeheim on December 2015.

## Traffic Agent (Supervisor) / Air Transat SCM, Swissport, Porto - Portugal

(January 2014 – October 2014)

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Provide logistical coordination and services for FBO Corporate Aircraft, Charter, Military and Head of State Aircrafts;
- Ensuring that productivity and performance criteria are met in the designated areas of responsibility including fulfilling regular performance and quality assessment reports;
- Making recommendations on all aspects of company ground handling operations whilst seeking to identify
  opportunities and improve performance and productivity;
- Diary management, typing documents, making weekly/monthly reports.

### Traffic Agent / Air Transat SCM, Servisair, Porto - Portugal

(*November 2010 – December 2013*)

Achievements and responsibilities:

- Supervise the check-in/ticketing/gate operations of all assigned flights
- Managing incoming requests for Executive Flights/Private Aircraft Operations
- Oversaw the daily ramp operations and provided leadership and support to all front line staffing
- Worked with corporate management to maximize operational performance in areas of on-time performance
- Maintained a high level of customer service

## **Education**

#### CESAE, Porto – Web & Mobile Developer

(June 2017 – October 2017)

#### A-levels:

- Front End Web development HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery
- Back End Python, PHP, MySQL
- Multi-Platform Mobile Application Development Cordova, Ionic, Node.js, AngularJS
- Mobile Development Frameworks with Xamarin / C# using Visual Studio
- CMS Drupal, WordPress
- Mobile Native Language Java using Android Studio.
- Development of Client / Server WEB Applications in PHP and MySQL

### Wyższa Szkoła Hotelarstwa i Gastronomii w Poznaniu/Poznan - Erasmus

(September 2009 – July 2010)

#### A-levels:

- Management A
- Tourist Market Analysis B
- Tourism Consultancy A
- Economics of Tourism and Recreation B

## Instituto Superior Politécnico Gaya/Porto

(September 2006 – November 2010)

#### A-levels:

- Marketing
- Tourism Legislation and regulations
- Preparation of Business Plans
- Management of Human Resources

## **Hobbies & Interests**

I'm frequently using my free time expanding my knowledge about aviation but sometimes I'm engaged in technology news, whether it can be regarding hardware, software, mobile, mobile applications or E-Sports. I'm also a frequent user of the gym, and like to eat well and spend time with my friends and family.

## References

Please feel free to browse through my Github Portfolio where you can find some of my proudest works ©

Personal and previous work references are available upon request.